<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A on Genetic Analysis Software | The Rockefeller List</title>
    <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A on Genetic Analysis Software | The Rockefeller List</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ACT</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/act/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/act/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name Analysis of Complex Traits
Version 1.1 (Mar 17, 2000)
Description It contains the following modules: ibd, calculates the proportion of gene shared identical by decent for a nuclear family; ibdn, (modified program of ERPA), which implements a method for assessing increased-allele sharing between all pairs of affected relatives within a pedigree; multic, multivariate analysis for complex traits; ml, estimation of variance components using maximum likelihood; ql, estimation of variance components using quasi likelihood; relcov, generates first degree relationship coefficients for extended families; sim2s, the simulation program that was used to test ACT; cage, Cohort Analysis for Genetic Epidemiology; gh: GeneHunter, heavily modified to assist multipoint calculation using multic; TDT: TDT programs written in SAS; gcc and f77 compilers are necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ADEGENET</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/adegenet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/adegenet/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Related R/ADEGENET   /** * RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS. * LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.com/admin/universalcode/#configuration-variables */ /* var disqus_config = function () { this.page.url = &#39;http://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/adegenet&#39;; // Replace http://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/adegenet with your page&#39;s canonical URL variable this.page.identifier = &#39;adegenet&#39;; // Replace adegenet with your page&#39;s unique identifier variable }; */ (function() { // REQUIRED CONFIGURATION VARIABLE: EDIT THE SHORTNAME BELOW // Don&#39;t ever inject Disqus on localhost--it creates unwanted // discussions from &#39;localhost:1313&#39; on your Disqus account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ADMIXMAP</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/admixmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/admixmap/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name Admixture mapping
Version 3.7 (2007)
Description ADMIXMAP is a general-purpose program for modelling admixture, using marker genotypes and trait data on a sample of individuals from an admixed population (such as African-Americans), where the markers have been chosen to have extreme differentials in allele frequencies between two or more of the ancestral populations between which admixture has occurred. The main difference between ADMIXMAP and classical programs for estimation of admixture such as ADMIX is that ADMIXMAP is based on a multilevel model for the distribution of individual admixture in the population and the stochastic variation of ancestry on hybrid chromosomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGEINF</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/ageinf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/ageinf/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Description inference of the age of a rare, selectively-neutral mutation
Author Jinko Graham
URL http://www.math.sfu.ca/~jgraham/Papers/Programs/AgeCode/
Language C
Reference Graham, Thompson (2000), &amp;ldquo;A coalescent model of ancestry for a rare allele&amp;rdquo;, Genetics, 156:375-384.   /** * RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS. * LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALBERT</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/albert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/albert/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name A Likelihood Based Estimation of Risk in Trios
Version 1.0 (May 2006)
Description ALBERT is a program that estimates genotype relative risks, genotyping error rates and population risk allele frequencies from marker genotype data in case-parent trios. ALBERT uses the distribution of trio marker genotypes to compute maximum likelihood estimates for the parameters.
Author  Adele Mitchell Elizabeth A Thompson (University of Washington)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALLASS</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/allass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/allass/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Version February 2002
Author  A Collins (email: arc@soton.ac.uk) NE Morton (University of Southampton, UK)
URL http://cedar.genetics.soton.ac.uk/pub/PROGRAMS/ALLASS
Language C
OS UNIX (SUN..)
EXE allass
Reference Collins, Morton (1998), &amp;ldquo;Mapping a disease locus by allelic association&amp;rdquo;, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences , 95:1741-1745; online manual   /** * RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALLEGRO</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/allegro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/allegro/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Version 2.0 (October 2005)
Description a faster version of GENEHUNTER and Allegro 1.2 (several degrees of increase of speed, can handle bigger families, up to 50 bits)
Author  Daniel F Gudbjartsson TA Thorvaldsson G Gunnarsson Augustine Kong A Ingolfsdottir (DeCode Genetics, Inc. Iceland) send email to: allegro@decode.is
URL http://www.decode.com/software/
Language C++
Reference D Gudbjartsson, K Jonasson, CA Kong (1999), &amp;ldquo;Fast multipoint linkage calculation with Allegro&amp;rdquo;, American Journal of Human Genetics, 65(suppl):A60.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALLELIX</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/allelix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/allelix/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name Allelix - Paternity Linkage Analysis Online
Version December 2001
Description One can enter the alleles of commonly used STR by clicking the mouse. The algorithm calculates the paternity index and the Essen-Moeller probability of kinship for the deficiency- and the trio case. Everybody can use the network-software online after registering. The usage on the internet is free. Academic users can ask me to unlock an option to display the details (formulas/frequencies etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALOHOMORA</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/alohomora/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/alohomora/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Version 0.33 (October 2009)
Description designed to facilitate genome-wide linkage studies performed with high-density single nucleotide polymorphism (SNP) marker panels such as the Affymetrix GeneChip&amp;reg; Human Mapping 10K Array.
Author  Franz Ruschendorf (email: fruesch@mdc-berlin.de) Peter Nurnberg
URL http://gmc.mdc-berlin.de/alohomora/
Language perl
OS MS-Window, Linux, UNIX (Solaris/..)
Reference Ruschendorf, Nurnberg (2005), &amp;ldquo;ALOHOMORA: a tool for linkage analysis using 10K SNP array data&amp;rdquo;, Bioinformatics, 21(9):2123-2125.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALP</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/alp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/alp/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name Automated Linkage Preprocessor
Version v1.40 (August 1995)
Description ALP is a Microsoft Windows application designed to analyse microsatellite DNA fragments separated on an Automated Laser Fluorescence sequencer.
Author  Alastair Brown (email: alastair.brown@hgu.mrc.ac.uk) Daryll Green Steve Woess (MRC Human Genetics Unit, Edinburgh, UK).
URL http://www.hgu.mrc.ac.uk/Softdata/ALP/
 ftp://ftp.hgu.mrc.ac.uk/pub/ALP
Language C
OS MS-Windows (3.1/95/NT)
EXE alpw.exe
Reference Mansfield, Brown, Green, Carothers, Morris, Evans, Wright (1994), &amp;ldquo;Automation of genetic linkage analysis using fluorescent microsatellite markers&amp;rdquo;, Genomics, 24(2):225-233.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altrans</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/altrans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/altrans/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Description Altrans measures alternative splicing levels based on quantifying exon-exon links between paired reads
Year 2015
Author  Ongen H. Dermitzakis E.T.
Reference Ongen H., Dermitzakis E.T. (2015) submitted
Tag splicing   /** * RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS. * LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALTREE</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/altree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/altree/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Description ALTREE performs these two phylogeny-based analysis: (1) it tests the association between a candidate gene and a disease; (2) it pinpoints markers (SNPs) that are putative disease susceptibility loci
Author  Claire Bardel (email: bardel@vjf.inserm.fr) Vincent Danjean Jean-Pierre Hugot Pierre Darlu Emmanuelle Génin
URL http://claire.bardel.free.fr/software.html
EXE altree, altree-convert, altree-add-s
Reference Bardel, Danjean, Hugot, Darlu, Genin (2005), &amp;ldquo;On the use of haplotype phylogeny to detect disease susceptibility loci&amp;rdquo;, BMC Genetics, 6:24.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMELIA</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/amelia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/amelia/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name Allele Matching Empirical Locus-specific Integrated Association test
Description AMELIA is a program that employs allele matching to analyse the effects of rare variants within a specific locus. There is increasing evidence that rare variants play a role in some complex traits, but their analysis is not straightforward. Locus-based tests become necessary due to low power in rare variant single-point association analyses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANALYZE</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/analyze/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/analyze/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Version 2.1 (feb 14, 1996)
Description a set of useful accessory programs to the LINKAGE package. It simplifies the performance of a large array of parametric and nonparametric tests for linkage and association on data entered in LINKAGE format pedigree and parameter files.
Author Joseph Terwilliger
URL  http://www.helsinki.fi/~tsjuntun/linkage/analyze/ http://linkage.cpmc.columbia.edu/index_files/Page434.htm ftp://ftp.ebi.ac.uk/pub/software/linkage_and_mapping/linkage_cpmc_columbia/analyze/
Language Pascal
OS UNIX (SunOS/Solaris/OSF1..)
EXE analysis (script), analyzeprep, downfreq, extract, (homog), homogpos, homogpre, hrrlamb, hrrlambprep, hrrmult, hrrprep, interpretation, locusorder, pedprepare, polylocus, sib2link, sibpairna, sibprepna, tdtlikena   /** * RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANCESTRY</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/ancestry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/ancestry/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Description This application aims at providing the user with an easy to use web-based user interface to compute individual ancestry estimates using the Maximum Likelihood Estimation method. This website also allows registered users to manage genotype and marker/allele frequency files. Registration is optional.
Author  Van-Anh Tran (email: vananh.tran@case.edu) Thomas Dyer Guo-Qiang Zhang Jill Barnholtz-Sloan (email: jsb42@case.edu)
URL http://ciil.case.edu:3000
Language Ruby on Rails, FORTRAN</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANCESTRYMAP</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/ancestrymap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/ancestrymap/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Version 2.0
Description ANCESTRYMAP screens through the genome in a recently mixed population such as African Americans, searching for segments with increased ancestry from one of the ancestral populations, which can indicate the position of disease genes
Author  Arti Tandon (email: atandon@broad.mit.edu) Nick Patterson (email: nickp@broad.mit.edu) David Reich.
URL http://genepath.med.harvard.edu/~reich/Software.htm
OS UNIX, Linux
Reference Patterson, Hattangadi, Lane, Lohmueller, Hafler, Oksenberg, Hauser, Smith, O&amp;rsquo;Brien, Altshuler, Daly, Reich (2004), &amp;ldquo;Methods for high-density admixture mapping of disease genes&amp;rdquo;, American Journal of Human Genetics, 74(5):97-1000   /** * RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANNOVAR</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/annovar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/annovar/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name functional ANNOtation of genetic VARiants
Version Feb 2010
Description ANNOVAR is an efficient software tool to utilize update-to-date information to functionally annotate genetic variants detected from diverse genomes (including human genome hg18, hg19, as well as mouse, worm, fly, yeast and many others). Given a list of variants with chromosome, start position, end position, reference nucleotide and observed nucleotides, ANNOVAR can perform: 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANTMAP</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/antmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/antmap/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Version 1.2 (June 2006)
Description Ordering markers when the number of loci is large is a special case of the traveling salesman problem. ANTMAP is a system based on the Ant Colony Optimization to solve this problem. ANYMAP performs segregation test, linkage grouping and locus ordering, and constructs a linkage map rapidly.
Author Hiroyoshi Iwata (email: iwata@lbm.ab.a.u-tokyo.ac.jp)
URL http://lbm.ab.a.u-tokyo.ac.jp/~iwata/antmap/
Language Java</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APE</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/ape/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/ape/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name Allelic Path Explorer
Version 1.0
Description Extends partially observed genotype data to the whole pedigree. Can be used for generating starting points for MCMC samplers and for checking that the genotype data are consistent with the pedigree structure.
Author  Matti Pirinen Dario Gasbarra (University of Helsinki, Finland)
URL http://www.helsinki.fi/~mpirinen/download
Language C
OS UNIX
Reference Pirinen, Gasbarra (2006), &amp;ldquo;Finding consistent gene transmission patterns on large and complex pedigrees&amp;rdquo;, IEEE/ACM cransactions on Computational Biology and Bioinformatics, 3(3):252-262   /** * RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APL-OSA</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/apl-osa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/apl-osa/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name Association in the Presence of Linkage with Ordered Subset Analysis
Description In the presence of genetic heterogeneity, APL-OSA can identify a genetically homogenous subset of families based on a trait-related covariate. APL-OSA then tests the relationship between the association statistics (i.e., the APL statistics) calculated based on the subset and the family-specific covariate. APL-OSA is based on the OSA method for linkage and the family-based association test, APL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APM</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/apm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/apm/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name Affected Pedigree-Member Method
Version July 1993
Author  Daniel E. Weeks (University of Oxford, University of Pittsburgh, email: dweeks@watson.hgen.pitt.edu) Mark Schroeder (email: mark@holmes.hgen.pitt.edu)
URL http://watson.hgen.pitt.edu/register/soft_doc.html registration page at: http://watson.hgen.pitt.edu/register
Language C and Pascal and FORTRAN
OS UNIX, VMS, MS-DOS
EXE apm, sim, apmmult, simmult, chapm, hist
Reference Weeks and Lange, American Journal of Human Genetics, 42(2):315-326 (1988). [abstract]   /** * RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARIEL</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/ariel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/ariel/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name Accumulation of Rare variants Integrated and Extended Locus-specific test
Description ARIEL explores the effects of rare variants within complex traits through locus-based analysis. There is increasing evidence that rare variants play a role in some complex traits, but their analysis is not straightforward. Locus-based tests become necessary due to low power in rare variant single-point association analyses. In addition, variant quality scores are available for sequencing data, but are rarely taken into account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARLEQUIN</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/arlequin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/arlequin/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name  French translation of &amp;ldquo;Arlecchino&amp;rdquo; French translation of &amp;ldquo;Arlecchino&amp;rdquo;, a character of the Italian &amp;ldquo;Commedia dell&amp;rsquo;Arte&amp;rdquo;. He has many aspects, but can switch among them very easily according to needs and necessities. Similarly, this software is about the study of genetic polymorphism.
Version 3.1 (September 2006)
Description an exploratory population genetics software environment able to handle large samples of molecular data (RFLPs, DNA sequences, microsatellites), while retaining the capacity of analyzing conventional genetic data (standard multi-locus data or mere allele frequency data).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARP.GEE</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/arp.gee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/arp.gee/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Version 0.1.0 (April 2005)
Description Simultaneously estimate a trait-locus position and its genetic effects for affected relative pairs (ARP) by one of two methods. Either allow a different trait-locus effect for each ARP type, or constrain the trait-locus effects according to the marginal effect of a single susceptibility locus. We include a goodness of fit statistic for the constrained model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP/ASPSHARE</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/aspaspshare/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/aspaspshare/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Version 1.2 (June 2002) (Warning: the earlier version contains a bug)
Description ASP a power calculator for gene mapping using a sibpair design (concordant or discordant). ASPSHARE complements ASP in that it allows rapid calculation of the expected ibd sharing at the trait locus, based upon the model parameters, and the incidence corresponding to the respective parameters.
Author Michael Krawczak</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASPEX</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/aspex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/aspex/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name Affected Sib Pairs EXclusion map
Version 2.5 (September 2003)
Description a set of programs for performing multipoint exclusion mapping of affected sibling pair data for discrete traits.
Author David Hinds (email: dahinds@users.sourceforge.net) Neil Risch (Stanford Univ)
URL  http://aspex.sourceforge.net/ ftp://lahmed.stanford.edu/pub/aspex
Language C, Tcl, Perl (the graphic script requires xmgr, available from ftp://ftp.teleport.com/pub/users/pturner/acegr)
OS UNIX (Solaris/SunOS/IRIX/OSF-1), Linux
EXE sib_ibd, sib_tdt, sib_phase, sib_map, sib_kin, sib_clean</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASSOCIATIONVIEWER</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/associationviewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/associationviewer/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Description AssociationViewer is a Java application used to display SNPs in a genetic context. Supplementary data (such as genes or LD plots) is downloaded from various public data sources on the fly and saved locally in a cache. Custom data can be added as supplementary tracks.
URL http://associationviewer.vital-it.ch/
Language Java
Reference Martin, Valsesia, Telenti, Xenarios, Stevenson (2009), &amp;ldquo;AssociationViewer: a scalable and integrated software tool for visualization of large-scale variation data in genomic context&amp;rdquo;, Bioinformatics, 25(5):662-663.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUTOSCAN</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/autoscan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/a/autoscan/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Version 1.0.1 (February 2000)
Description a helper program to automate the tedious process of the creation of input files from genotype data of genome-wide scans
Author  T Hiekkalinna L Peltonen (UCLA)
URL http://www.helsinki.fi/~tsjuntun/autoscan/
Language C and UNIX-shell (Bourne)
OS UNIX (Solaris/DEC-UNIX)
EXE autostart, autoscan10.sh
Reference American Journal of Human Genetics, supp, 65 . ( abstract) (1999)   /** * RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>