<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Q on Genetic Analysis Software | The Rockefeller List</title>
    <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Q on Genetic Analysis Software | The Rockefeller List</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>QGENE</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/qgene/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/qgene/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Version 4.0.2
Description A free, computationally effecient, easy-to-use Java program for comparative analyses of QTL mapping data and population simulation.
Author  Roby Joehanes Zhigang Guo Prashanth Boddhireddy J Clare Nelson (Kansas State University)
URL http://www.qgene.org/
 http://coding.plantpath.ksu.edu/qgene/
Language Java
Reference Nelson (1997), &amp;ldquo;QGENE: software for marker-based genomic analysis and breeding&amp;rdquo;, Molecular Breeding, 3:239-245. [abstract]   /** * RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QMSIM</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/qmsim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/qmsim/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name Qtl and Marker SIMulator
Version 1.0
Description QMSim was designed to simulate a wide range of genetic architectures and population structures in livestock. Large scale genotyping data and complex pedigrees can be efficiently simulated. QMSim is a family based simulator, which can also take into account predefined evolutionary features, such as LD, mutation, bottlenecks and expansions. The simulation is basically carried out in two steps: In the first step, a historical population is simulated to establish mutation-drift equilibrium and, in the second step, recent population structures are generated, which can be complex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QTDT</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/qtdt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/qtdt/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name Quantitative (Trait) Transmission/Disequilibrium Test
Version 2.5.1 (January 2005)
Description Performs linkage disequilibrium (TDT) and association analysis for quantitative traits. Includes support for the methods of Abecasis et al. (2000), Fulker et al. (1999), Monks et al. (1998), Allison (TDTQ5, 1997) and Rabinowitz (1997). Supports families of any size, with or without parental information. Includes simple variance components modelling. Interfaces with SimWalk2 for IBD estimation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QTL CAFE</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/qtl-cafe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/qtl-cafe/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Version May 1998
Description providing a user freiendly way to perform QTL analysis. The software currently allows 3 types of QTL analysis: (1) single marker ANOVA. (2) marker regression. (3) interval mapping by regression.
URL http://www.biosciences-labs.bham.ac.uk/Kearsey/
OS Java   /** * RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS. * LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QTL Cartographer</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/qtl-cartographer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/qtl-cartographer/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Version Window version 2.5 (September 2006)
Description A program to map quantitative traits sing a map of molecular markers.
Author  Christopher J. Basten Bruce S. Weir Zhao-Bang Zeng Shengchu Wang (Dept Statistics, North Carolina State University);
URL http://statgen.ncsu.edu/qtlcart/cartographer.html
 ftp://statgen.ncsu.edu/pub/qtlcart/
OS UNIX, MS-Windows, MacOS
EXE rmap, rqtl, rcross, qstats, lrmapqtl, srmapqtl, zmapqtl, prune, preplot, eqtl, qtlcart
Reference Basten,Weir,Zeng (1994), &amp;ldquo;Zmap-a QTL cartographer&amp;rdquo;, in Proceedings of the 5th World Congress on Genetics Applied to Livestock Production: Computing Strategies and Software, vol 22, eds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QTL EXPRESS</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/qtl-express/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/qtl-express/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Version August 2005
Description A web-based user-friendly package to map Quantitative Trait Loci in outbred populations. Population structures catered for are line crosses, halfsib families, nuclear families and sibpairs. Permutation tests to determine empirical significance levels and bootstrapping to estimate empirical confidence intervals of QTL locations are optional. Fixed effects/covariates can be fitted and models may include single or multiple QTL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QTL-ALL</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/qtl-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/qtl-all/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name QTL Analysis and Linkage Library
Description QTL-ALL is a software package designed to make as many as possible of the new statistics (e.g. score statistics) widely available. The software consists of a MEGA2-like interface for data analysis preparation and a library of R routines that computes linkage statistics. QTL-ALL reads in input data, creates re-formatted output data files, calls external IBD-generation software such as MERLIN or SIMWALK2, then computes statistics using our R library, and finally produces tables and plots of statistics and p-values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QTLNETWORK</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/qtlnetwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/qtlnetwork/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Version 2.0
Description QTLNetwork is a software package for mapping and visualizing the genetic architecture underlying complex traits for experimental populations derived from a cross between two inbred lines.
Author  Jian Yang Chengcheng Hu Xiuzi Ye Jun Zhu (Zhejiang University)
URL http://ibi.zju.edu.cn/software/qtlnetwork
Reference Yang, Hu, Hu, Yu, Xia, Ye, Zhu (2008), &amp;ldquo;QTLNetwork: mapping and visualizing genetic architecture of complex traits in experimental populations&amp;rdquo;, Bioinformatics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QU-GENE</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/qu-gene/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/qu-gene/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name QUantitative GENEtics
Version v1 (1998)
Description A package for quantitative analysis of genetic models
Author  D. Podlich (email: d.podlich@mailbox.uq.edu.au) M. Cooper (email: m.cooper@mailbox.uq.edu.au)
URL http://pig.ag.uq.edu.au/qu-gene/ (not available)
Language Fortran
OS MS-Windows
EXE qugene.exe
Reference Podlich, Cooper (1998), &amp;ldquo;QU-GENE: a simulation platform for quantitative analysis of genetic models&amp;rdquo;, Bioinformatics. 14:632-653. Online manual: http://pig.ag.uq.edu.au/qu-gene/manual.htm   /** * RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QUANTO</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/quanto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/quanto/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Version 1.2.1 (January 2007)
Description Quanto is a program that computes sample size or power for association studies of genes, environmental factors, gene-environment interaction, or gene-gene interaction. Available study designs for a disease (binary) outcome include the unmatched case-control, matched case-control, case-sibling, case-parent, and case-only designs. Study designs for a quantitative tra it include independent individuals and case parent designs. Quanto is a 32-bit Windows application requiring Windows 95, 98, NT, 2000, ME or XP to run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QUTIE</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/qutie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/q/qutie/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name Case-Control RAre Variant Analysis Tool
Description Enabling the analysis of rare variants in large-scale case control and quantitative trait association studies. CCRaVAT (Case-Control Rare Variant Analysis Tool) and QuTie (Quantitative Trait) are software packages that enable efficient large-scale analysis of rare variants across specific regions or genome-wide. These programs implement a rare variant super-locus or collapsing method that investigates the accumulation of rare variant alleles in either a case-control or quantitative trait study design.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>