<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>J on Genetic Analysis Software | The Rockefeller List</title>
    <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/j/</link>
    <description>Recent content in J on Genetic Analysis Software | The Rockefeller List</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/j/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>J/QTL</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/j/jqtl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/j/jqtl/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Description J/QTL is a Java GUI for the popular QTL data analysis software R/QTL. It provides a flexible and powerful working environment for users to perform a variety of tasks.
Author  Hao Wu
 Lei Wu (Jackson Lab) (email: jqtl@jax.com)
  URL http://www.jax.org/staff/churchill/labsite/software/Jqtl/index.html
Language Java${disqus_tpl}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JENTI</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/j/jenti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/j/jenti/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Description An efficient tool for mining complex inbred genealogies that identify clusters of individuals sharing the same expected amount of relatedness is described. Additionally it allows for the reconstruction of sub-pedigrees suitable for genetic mapping in a systematic way.
URL http://www.jenti.org
Language Java
Reference Falchi, Fuchsberger (2008), &amp;ldquo;Jenti: an efficient tool for mining complex inbred genealogies&amp;rdquo;, Bioinformatics, 24(5):724-726.${disqus_tpl}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JLIN</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/j/jlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/j/jlin/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name a Java based LINkage disequilibrium plotter
Version 1.5.2 (March 2006)
Description JLIN (Java LINkage disequilibrium plotter) is designed for customisable, intuitive visualisation of LD analysis across all common computing platforms. Customisation allows the researcher to choose particular visualisation, statistical measures and measurement ranges. JLIN also allows the researcher to export images of the LD visualisation in several common document formats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JOINMAP</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/j/joinmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/j/joinmap/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name Software for the calculation of genetic linkage maps
Version 4 (October 2006)
Description Construction of genetic linkage maps for several types of mapping populations: BC1, F2, RILs, (doubled) haploids, outbreeders full-sib family. Can combine (&amp;lsquo;join&amp;rsquo;) data derived from several sources into an integrated map. Further: linkage group determination, automatic phase determination for outbreeders full-sib family, several diagnostics, and map charts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JPSGCS</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/j/jpsgcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/j/jpsgcs/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name Java Programs for Statistical Genetics and Computational Statistics
Description These programs have been developed since 2002 to address problems in statistical genetics. However, they include several programs and packages that may be more generally useful, for instance, programs to draw and manipulate graphs, simulation programs, and programs to estimate graphical models.
Author Alun Thomas
URL http://balance.med.utah.edu/wiki/index.php/JPSGCS
Language Java</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>