<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>O on Genetic Analysis Software | The Rockefeller List</title>
    <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/o/</link>
    <description>Recent content in O on Genetic Analysis Software | The Rockefeller List</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/o/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OLORIN</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/o/olorin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/o/olorin/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Version October 2011
Description Olorin is an interactive filtering tool for next generation sequencing data coming from the study of large complex disease pedigrees. Olorin, is a tool which integrates gene flow output from Merlin and next generation sequencing data. Users can interactively filter and prioritize variants based on haplotype sharing across different sets of selected individuals and allele frequency in reference datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ONEMAP</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/o/onemap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/o/onemap/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Related R/ONEMAP${disqus_tpl}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSA</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/o/osa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/o/osa/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Full Name Ordered Subset Analysis
Version 2.1
Description OSA allows the researcher to evaluate evidence for linkage even when heterogeneity is present in a data set. This is not an unusual occurrence when studying diseases of complex origin. Families are ranked by covariate values in order to test evidence for linkage among homogeneous subsets of families. Because families are ranked, a priori covariate cutpoints are not necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSIRIS</title>
      <link>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/o/osiris/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaow.github.io/genetic-analysis-software/o/osiris/</guid>
      <description>Record added by Jurg Ott (the original Rockefeller list)
Version 1.1
Description OSIRIS is a tool for the retrieval of articles from MEDLINE related to the sequence variants reported for a human gene. The variations considered are single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs), insertion/deletion polymorphisms (indel), microsatellite, and named variations (e.g. Alu sequences).
Author  Julio Bonis
 Laura Ines Furlong Ferran Sanz (University of Pompeu Fabra, Spain) (email: fsanz@imim.es)
  URL http://ibi.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>